Guide to the George Breitman Papers TAM.169
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV. Writings, Lectures, and Interviews, 1919-1989; 4.5 Linear Feet in 26 containers
  - Subseries C: Malcolm X, 1964-1989
    - "Malcolm X: The Cairo Interview", July 17, 1964; cuid42817 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0023)
      Conducted by Milton Henry; Broadcasted in Detroit, Michigan on the GOAL Show; Interview conducted in Cairo, Egypt shortly after Malcolm presented a memorandum on the conditions of Black people in America to the Organization of Afro-American Unity
      Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
    - Malcolm X Compilation Tape, July, 1964 - November, 1965; cuid42863 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0089)
      This tape includes The Barry Gray Show, "Open Mind," and "Editor Speaks"
    - "Racism is the cancer that is destroying America," article by Malcolm X, August, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - "Zionist Logic," article by Malcolm X, The Egytian Gazette, September 17, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Panel Discussion on the Congo, The Barry Gray Show, New York City, November 28, 1964; cuid42818 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0026)
      Featuring Hugh H. Smythe, Sanford Griffith, Fourth Internationalist Tendency, James H. Robinson, and Malcolm X.
    - Organization of Afro-American Unity Homecoming Rally, Audubon Ballroom, New York City, November 29, 1964; cuid42823
      While there is some overlap in content, different speakers appear on each recording.
      - Audiocassette, cuid42823A (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0033)
        Preservation Note: The audio quality is extremely poor, with muffled and muted sound that is difficult to decipher.
      - Audio reel, cuid42823B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0077)
        Preservation Note: The overall volume is very low. There's a jump cut on track 2 near the 12 minute mark.
    - Malcolm X Compilation Tape, November - December, 1964; cuid42862 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0086)
      Includes an appearance on the Les Crane Show (December 2, 1964) and an event at the Audubon Ballroom (November 29, 1964)
    - Malcolm X on The Les Crane Show, December 2, 1964; cuid42819 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0027)
      Preservation Note: The audio quality on side 1 is poor. Side 2 is blank.
    - The HARYOU-ACT Rally with Guest Speaker Malcolm X, December 12, 1964; cuid42820
      Rally for Harlem Youth Opportunities Unlimited + Associated Community Teams
      - Full event recording, cuid42820A (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0028)
        Preservation Note: Side 1 has some audio distortion; side 2 has audio distortion and channel shifting.
      - Part two, cuid42820B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0097)
        Preservation Note: The audio quality is poor; The audio was captured in two passes at 4 track mono. The recording speed was 1.875 ips and the transfer speed 3.75 ips, so the audio was digitally stretched.
      - Part one, cuid42820C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0098)
        Preservation Note: The overall volume is very low and the audio quality is poor; On track 2 at 00:12:12 there's a jump cut.
    - Malcolm X at the Audubon Ballroom, December 13, 1964; cuid42824 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0034)
      Featuring Malcolm X, Dick Gregory, Sheik Abdul Rahman Muhammad Babu
    - Malcolm X at Harvard Law School Forum (typescript, Edited by Breitman), December 16, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Malcolm X at the Audubon Ballroom, December 20, 1964; cuid42825 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0035)
      Featuring Malcolm X and Fannie Lou Hamer
      Preservation Note: Audio quality is very poor.
    - Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party Rally, December 20, 1964; cuid42826 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0036)
      A support rally for the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party featuring Fannie Lou Hamer, Malcolm X, and Jesse Gray
      Preservation Note: Both sides have poor audio quality, though side 2 is not as bad.
    - Malcolm X on Community Corner Radio Program, WADO, December 27, 1964; cuid42827 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0037)
      Hosted by Bernice Bass
      Preservation Note: The audio has signal distortion.
    - "Malcolm X Talks to Young People", December 31, 1964; cuid42828 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0038)
      A meeting with SNCC workers from McComb, Mississippi
      Preservation Note: Periodic interference with the microphone can be heard.
    - Malcolm X Speaks at the Audubon Ballroom, New York City, December, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Malcolm X Compilation Tape, December, 1964 - February, 1965; cuid42865 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0091)
      This tape includes Harlem Church Rally (December 20, 1964) and Hamer's Rally (February 27, 1965).
    - Interviews About Malcolm X -- Elijah Muhammad and Wallace D. Muhammad, 1964; cuid42821 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0029)
    - Malcolm X: The Struggle for Freedom Movie Soundtrack, circa 1964; cuid42853 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0071)
    - Articles in The Militant on Malcolm X - list of, 1964-1965 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Organization of Afro-American Unity, 1964-1965 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Malcolm X Compilation Tape, 1964-1965; cuid42869 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0104)
      Side 1: Malcolm X -- Ford Auditorium, Detroit, February 14, 1965 Side 2: Malcolm X -- "The Ballot or the Bullet," Detroit, April 1964; Malcolm X -- Cairo Interview, July 24, 1964
    - Malcolm X on The Pierre Berton Show, January, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Malcolm X Speaks to Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, Harlem, January 1, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Group on Advanced Leadership Show, Emergency Rally with Fannie Lou Hamer, January 2, 1965; cuid42860 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0082)
    - "Prospects for Freedom in 1965" by Malcolm X, Militant Labor Forum, New York City, January 5-7, 1965; cuid42861
      Chair: Clifford DeBerry
      - Speech one with Q+A, cuid42861A (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0039)
      - Speech one, cuid42861B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0085)
      - Speech two with Q+A, cuid42861C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0113)
        Preservation Note: The audio quality of track 2 is poor.
    - Malcom X Interviews Young Socialist, January 18, 1965; cuid42867
      - Part one, cuid42867A (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0099)
      - Full interview, cuid42867B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0100)
        Preservation Note: The overall audio quality is poor, but the first 2 minutes of Side 1 is especially bad.
    - Malcolm X on Afro-American History, Audubon Ballroom, New York City, January 24, 1965; cuid42829 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0040)
    - Malcolm X Interview, Dartmouth College, WDCR, January 26, 1965; cuid42830 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0041)
      Interviewer: Ken Sharpe
    - Harry Rine Interview with Malcolm X, WBAI-FM, January 28, 1965; cuid42856 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0076)
      A note included with the tape reads "Militant Labor Forum NY - April 8, 1964 - Malcolm X - 1st Copy"
    - "Malcolm X: Two Interviews", January, 1965; cuid42831 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0042)
      Side One: The Young Socialist Interview by Barnes and Sheppard (January 18, 1965); Side Two: The WBAI Interview by Harry Ring (January 28, 1965).
    - "Malcolm X: The Last Message", Detroit, Michigan, February 13, 1965; cuid42832 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0043)
    - Malcolm X at the Ford Auditorium, February 14, 1965; cuid42870
      - Part one, cuid42870A (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0105)
      - Part two, cuid42870B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0106)
        Preservation Note: The first 43 seconds of side 1 are very muted and the audio quality is poor. The first 30 seconds of side 2 are very muted and the audio quality is poor.
      - Part three, cuid42870C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0109)
      - Full speech, cuid42870D (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0110)
    - Malcolm X at Organization of Afro-American Unity Rally, Audubon Ballroom, New York City, February 15, 1965; cuid42833 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0044)
    - Malcolm X on Contact with Stan Bernard, WINS New York City, February 18, 1965; cuid42834
      Participants: Malcolm X, Aubrey Barnett, Gordon Hall
      - Audiocassette, cuid42834A (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0045)
      - Audio reel, cuid42834C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0081)
    - "The Legacy of Malcolm X" Interview on the Barry Grey Show, New York City, February 28, 1965; cuid42835 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0046)
      Featuring Leon Ameer, Percy Sutton, Constance Baker Motley, Bayard Rustin, John A. Morsell
    - Malcolm X Speaks to Harlem Domestic Peace CORPS, December 12, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Speech at Harvard Law School Forum by Malcolm X, December 15, 1965; cuid42836 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0048)
    - Autobiography of Malcolm X uncorrected proof, Breitman notes, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Breitman Correspondence -- General, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Malcolm X Speaks Edited proof typescript, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Assassination of Malcolm X -- Articles, Clippings, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Breitman Correspondence -- General, January, 1966 - June, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Breitman Correspondence -- General, July, 1966 - August, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Breitman Correspondence -- General, September, 1966 - December, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Breitman Correspondence -- Cleaver, Eldridge, November, 1966 - November, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Breitman Correspondence -- General, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Breitman Correspondence -- General, 1968-1982 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Breitman -- "The Impact of Malcolm X", November, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Breitman -- Untitled manuscript on Malcolm X, circa 1966 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Breitman -- "Last year of Malcolm X" typescript, 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "A Tribute to the Revolutionary Impact of Malcolm X on Black Youth", Detroit, Michigan, February 23, 1968; cuid42839 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0051)
      Featuring Judy Watts, Bob Higgins, and John Watson; Friday Night Socialist Forum
      Preservation Note: Side 2 has a poorer audio quality than side 1.
    - Novack, George on "Malcolm X," at Militant Labor Forum, San Francisco, May 1976 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Lee, Paul -- Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "Malcolm X and the Black Revolution" by Eugene Victor Wolfenstein, Los Angeles NAM Socialist Community School, October 16, 1981; cuid42847 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0061)
    - "The Politics of Malcolm X," a Radio Documentary by Sheiron Allen, 1981; cuid42846 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0060)
    - Breitman -- Articles and notes about Malcolm X, undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Lomax, Louis E., undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Malcolm X -- Articles and Transcriptions, undated (Box 46, Folder 1, 2)
    - Malcolm X -- Music by Dennis Brown, Undated; cuid42851 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0068)
  - Subseries D: African Americans, 1939-1971
    - Johnson, J. R (C.L.R. James) Preliminary notes on the Negro Question, 1939 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Parker, Albert (George Breitman) list of articles, 1939-1945 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Parker, Albert (aka George Breitman) Militant articles, 1940-1943 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Parker, Albert (George Breitman pseudonym) correspondence, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Guerin, Daniel/Negroes on the march 1956: Breitman correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Black organizations - documents, 1960s (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Black Struggle Report" by George Breitman, 1963; cuid42901 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0153)
      Given at 1963 Socialist Workers Party Convention
    - Northern Negro Grassroots Leadership Conference -- Detroit, Michigan, November 8-10, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Freedom Now Party: Cruse, Harold - letter, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Freedom Now Party documents, 1963-1966 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Breitman - Theory of the Negro struggle (4 classes), 1964 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Freedom Now Party: Breitman correspondence, 1964 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Freedom Now Party: Breitman writings, circa 1964-1965 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Freedom Now Party: Interview with Reverend Cleage (32 pages), circa 1965 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Breitman "In defense of Black Power", Oct 1966 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - By any means necessary (proposed magazine), 1967 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Novack, George - The meaning of the ghetto revolts [22 pages], 1967 (Box 48, Folder 2.5)
    - Panel Discussion on Black Power at Socialist Scholars Conference, September, 1967; cuid42844
      Speakers: Prof. Raymond S. Franklin, Prof. Gilbert Osasky, James Boggs, Ivanhoe Donaldson
      - Part one, cuid42844A (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0057)
        Preservation Note: The first 47 seconds of side 1 have poor audio quality.
      - Part two, cuid42844B (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0058)
    - Militant Labor Forum on Black Separatism, New York City, December 1, 1967; cuid42837 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0049)
      Featuring Robert S. Browne, John Wilson, and Robert Vernon
    - Eldridge Cleaver at San Francisco State, 1968; cuid42838 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0050)
    - "Black Control of the Black Community: Strategy for Liberation" by Tony Thomas, New York City, April 4, 1969; cuid42840 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0052)
    - Breitman "Race prejudice: when it began, when it will end", 1971 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Yolanda King and Attalah Shabazz Discussion at Black Women's Forum, Los Angeles, January 22, 1983; cuid42849 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0065)
    - Breitman correspondence, undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Breitman "Shifts in the Negro Question", undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Breitman writings, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - The Communist movement and the Negroes 38 page galley proof, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Lectures on Afro-American History by George Weissmann, Undated; cuid42854
      - Lecture one, cuid42854A (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0072)
        Preservation Note: Side 1 has channel shifting and poor audio quality at the beginning.
      - Lecture two, cuid42854B (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0073)
      - Lecture three, cuid42854C (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0074)
        Preservation Note: The audio quality is poor overall, but the first 2 minutes of side 1 is especially bad.
    - Socialist Workers Party Internal Bulletin - Negro Question (list of articles, 1942-1958), undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Untitled typescript (partial) - for book on Socialist Workers Party and Negro Question?, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Subseries E: Cannon, James P., 1919-1984
    James P. Cannon (1890-1974) was an American Trotskyist and a member of the Socialist Workers Party and Fourth International. This series contains Cannon's correspondence, writings and interviews, and Breitman's correspondence regarding the editing and publication of Cannon's writings.
    - Breitman: correspondence re Cannon, 1974-1985 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence - Glotzer, Al, 1977-1981 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence - Prometheus research library, 1984-1985 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Breitman (and others): lists, indexes of Cannon materials, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Cannon correspondence 1924-1060 - chronological list, 59 pages, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Cannon correspondence - Dunne, Vincent [letters to], circa 1932-1940 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Cannon correspondence - Houghton Library, Harvard, 1933-1940 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Cannon correspondence - Swabeck, Arne (Prinkipo, Turkey), 1933 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1922-1927 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents - CPUSA Political Committee Minutes, Oct 1928 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1929-1935 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1936-1938 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1939-1949 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1951-1955 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1956-1957 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1959-1967 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Cannon "The Debs centennial" typescript, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Cannon interviews (Dixon/Omari; Emiliano/Miguel), undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Cannon interview (by Harry Ring), 1973-1974 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Cannon interview (Sidney Lens), 1974 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Cannon personal papers and library - post mortem inventory, 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Cannon "The pre-communist revolutionary movement in the US" (2 lectures): Sep-54, Sep 1954 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Cannon - Trotsky correspondence [copies from other sources], 1936-1940 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Cannon: Writings (mainly newspaper articles), 1919-1934 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Glotzer, Al. "Reminiscences of J.P.C." (typescript), 1975 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Morgan, Jeanne "The Cannon journal" (typescript), undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Wald, Alan "Cannonites and Shachtmanites" (typescript), 1984 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Wohlforth, Tim "James P. Cannon: in defense of a great revolutionary" (typescript), undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Subseries F: Trotsky, Leon, 1926-1986
    Leon Trotsky (1879-1940) was a Soviet Russian politician, socialist, and political theorist. Subseries E contains a selection of Leon Trotsky's correspondence and writings (most are photocopies of archival and published materials), including several letters by leading U.S. Trotskyists, sent from Prinkipo to their American comrades, one small file of Natalia Trotsky correspondence, another of Hansen-Trotsky correspondence, and Breitman's correspondence regarding his editing and publication of the works of Trotsky.
    - Trotsky, Leon - writings [compiled by John Wright], 1926-1947 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Shachtman, Max/Trotsky, Leon correspondence, 1929-1932 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - La Verite- indexes 1-255, 1929-1936, undated (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - La Verite- table of contents 1-255, 1929-1936, undated (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Trotsky/Cannon correspondence, 1929-1940 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Glotzer, Al correspondence, 1929-1977 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Trotsky, Leon - letters, memos to American comrades, 1930-1941 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Reich, Wilhelm, 1931-1935 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Swabeck, Arne Letters to Cannon, from Prinkipo, March 1933 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Swabeck, Arne/Trotsky, Leon: exchange of letters, in Prinkipo, March 1933 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Shachtman, Max "Dear comrades..." [from Bujukada, Turkey], June 1933 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Trotsky, Leon: Cannon, letters to [compiled by John Wright], 1937-1972 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Hansen, Joseph/Trotsky, Leon correspondence, 1937-1980 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Discussion with Lund [Les Trotskyistes] transcript, 28 pages [Les Trotskyistes, Cannon, Dobbs, Hansen, etc.], June 1940 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Trotsky, Natalia Sedov, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - "Trotsky and America" by James Cannon, September 2, 1956; cuid1048 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0001, Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0147)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Breitman correspondence, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Life of Leon Trotsky [film] reviews, 1972-1974 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Derry, Felix Louis - Les Trotskyistes, Trotsky et al Question D'Alsace Lorraine, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 6.5)
    - Institute Leon Trotsky (Paris), 1977-1981 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Writings of Leon Trotsky (1929-1940) - celebration of completion of publication, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Evans, Les "An open break with Trotsky's permanent revolution" typescript, circa 1982 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Catalog of Trotsky's published works - prepared for Pioneer Publishers, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Lore, Ludwig We Try Again - Chapter 1 "Parting of the ways" typescript, undated (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Novack, George "How a bureaucracy thinks" [review of Les Trotskyistes manuscript "The philosophical tendencies of bureaucratization"], undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Revolution - table of contents and index, 1935-1939, undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Shachtman at 64 by Tom Kreuger, undated (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Trotsky/Sedov correspondence, list of letters, undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Trotsky, Leon - writings copies/translations, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Unser Wort - table of contents, 1-104, 1933-1941, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Subseries G: Skoglund, Carl, 1942-1982
    Carl Skoglund (1884-1960) was a Swedish-American Trotskyist and Teamster leader based in Minneapolis. Subseries G: Skoglund, Carl include's Breitman's correspondedence with Skoglund regarding a biography, as well as portions of the unpublished typescript.
    - Alien hearing transcript, 1942 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Deportation hearing transcript, May 1954 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Auto-biographical sketches, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Turning point for Labor video project, 1979-1982 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1980 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Arne Swabeck on Carl Skoglund, November 29, 1980; cuid1049 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0056)
      Audio quality is poor
    - Ostberg, Kjell correspondence re Skoglund in Sweden, 1980-1982 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - FBI correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Oscar Coover on Skoglund, January 11, 1981; cuid42885 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0135)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Carl Skoglund research project, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Skoglund centenary, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Carl Skoglund Talks, Undated; cuid1047 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0067)
      Subjects include Weissman Interviews, religion, social life, Sweden
    - FBI files, undated (Box 56, Folder 2, 3, 4, 5)
    - Furst, Randy correspondence re Skoglund in Minnesota, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Research file, undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Weissman / Skoglund Interviews and Transcripts, undated; cuid42802
      - Transcripts (Box 55, Folder 13)
      - Audiocassette, cuid42802 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0129)
  - Subseries H: Wald, Alan, 1974-1986
    Alan Wald (1946-) is an American professor of literature who focuses on communist writers from the 20th century.
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, Jan 1978-Jun 1978 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, Jul 1978-Dec 1978 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1983 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Wald, Alan: Glotzer, Al - interview notes, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Wald, Alan (re) Mangan, Sherry, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 3)